- [birds chirping]
- [ALDARP] So...
you just brazenly show up
at my abode, is that the deal?
Well, yeah,
but very reluctantly.
Unbelievable.
It's like you have
a fatal allergy
to staying outta trouble.
I guess I'm stuck
helping you out,
but I don't ever
wanna hear you whining
about me anymore!
Because you're just
as bad, Kazuma!
He certainly is!
So, he can hardly refer to us
as "troublemakers"
anymore now, can he?
Of course, as his friends,
we'd still much rather
help him out
than leave him
to his own devices! -[graons]
Well, if it isn't the demented
little wizard girl.
You'd better not be planning
to blow away
my valuable property
as you did before.
Excuse me?
[grunts]
That said,
I do feel somewhat insulted
that the unsavory rumors
people have been
spreading about me
are being so easily believed.
Th-This is only one aspect
of the ongoing investigation.
[ALDARP] Oh! Of course.
I understand, Lady Dustiness.
You, at least,
are welcome to stay
- as long as you desire.
- Huh.
You heard him!
He said we can stay here
- as long as we want to!
- [ALL] Huh.
I get the biggest guest room,
you guys! Ha ha!
That's not fair, Kazuma!
I want the one closest
to the dining room!
[MEGUMIN] I would be best
suited to... -Hey,
- wait just a--
- ...the room with the highest
altitude possible!
Damn it, Aqua! Who told ya
you could come up here?!
- I am truly sorry.
- [whimpering]
Forgive them.
[whimpering]
You certainly seem
to have your hands full,
Lady Dustiness.
I apologize.
- [indistinct chatter]
- I'm so sorry.
So sorry!
[KAZUMA]
My plans have definitely taken
a strange twist.
Man, I wish I was back
in that castle.
But, your big brother's
gonna try, Iris!
If a thief's coming,
I bet it'll be at night.
Huh?
What's that room?
[laughing]
[door closes]
[gasps] Oh, it's you.
- [KAZUMA] I'm Kazuma.
- Nothing of note in here.
I wouldn't just wander around
unless you have
a very good reason.
[gasps]
- Whatcha lookin' at?
- Wait!
Hmm.
[humming]
[KAZUMA]
The baths?
Is this a magic mirror?
Making sure
it's in good condition
since Darkness is here, huh?
So, so, would you care
to accompany me?
Obviously, I won't be swayed
by your wicked ways.
Now, go on and get outta here.
I'm using this room.
Ugh!
[gasps] What do you mean,
you're going to be using it.
Come on, man,
quit thinkin' like
you're some kinda deviant.
I'm gonna sleep in this room
to keep my friends
from getting' creeped on!
Don't try it!
I cannot allow
a rapscallion like you
to gaze upon
Lalatina's nubile body!
I really hate
to break it to ya,
but I've already been in
the bath with Darkness before!
Do you want me to let
the whole mansion know
what you've got in this room?
Time for us to make a deal.
If you don't want your
entire maid staff pissed off,
- keep your mouth shut!
- Huh.
Being constantly harassed
is just part
of a maid's job description!
I should be the one
who's making you an offer.
I'm not exactly sure why,
but I get the distinct feeling
that you and I
are birds of a feather.
Why not choose
the much friendlier option?
Ba-dump! Ba-dump!
[DARKNESS] That is quite
an interesting offer.
In fact, perhaps you should
go over the terms for us.
♪
[BOTH] This pervert
was trying to look in on...
- [thumps]
- [both gasps]
[KAZUMA]
I'm sorry.
It's been three days
since we got here.
Mansion life
is comfortable enough.
But there hasn't really
been much happening so far.
♪
[munching]
Hm.
Hey, are you eating
your lunch now, Kazuma?
- Yeah. Good morning.
- Hm?
Actually,
it's the afternoon already.
Listen, I was awake all night
keepin' a lookout
for the thief,
thank you very much!
Besides,
if what I heard is true,
you were stayin' up late
just about every night
- while I was away from Axel.
- [gasps]
Somebody told you that, huh?
You were taken so suddenly,
I was getting really worried!
But more importantly,
have you found any signs
of the thief, yet?
What got you so anxious?
You were seriously worried
about me, huh?
Guess that's pretty cute.
It-It's only because you
always manage to get yourself
into more trouble,
despite being such a weakling!
You die at the drop
of a hat, too!
Hey, it's not as if I try
to get into trouble!
Just like I wasn't dying
on purpose either, all right?
Hm.
[KAZUMA] Oh, feels like
I'm living in a rom-com!
Oh, man, are you serious?
How am I supposed to react
when you're being so friggin'
sweet all of a sudden?
- [MEGUMIN] Kazuma.
- [gasps]
When you're finished
eating your meal,
would you like
to join me for a date?
Ba-dump!
♪
[MEGUMIN]
Explosion!
[explosion]
- Huh.
- How did I know
it'd be somethin' like this?
[gulping]
- [exhales]
- [gasps]
[MEGUMIN]
Plosion!
[explosion]
What's that?
The Devil King Army?
[all laughing]
- [MEGUMIN] Sion!
- [explosion]
[people shrieking]
[KAZUMA] You know
the capital's already gettin'
a lot of complaints
about you, right?
[MEGUMIN] My name has begun
to resound, is that it?
[KAZUMA] Maybe
I should've just had you learn
advanced magic after all.
[MEGUMIN] I don't
appreciate that, Kazuma!
Not one little bit!
[KAZUMA]
So, after that.
[AQUA]
Hey, do you think you can screw
with a hardcore water Goddess?
[KAZUMA] Aqua spent
the entire week drinking up
all of the best booze
in the mansion.
Well, it was then
that my Explosion magic
burst forth laying waste
to the despicable general
of the Devil King's army, Hans!
Then came the time I battled
another general, Sylvia.
[KAZUMA] Megumin
regaled us daily, at length,
about her heroic triumphs.
And, as for me...
Excuse me, Miss,
I think it's about that time.
- Could I get my usual massage?
- Huh.
And, for dinner tonight,
can we have
giant beef sukiyaki?
Also, the down blanket
should be coming in soon,
just put it on my bed.
[ALDARP]
Uh, my dear Lady Dustiness.
[gasps]
[ALDARP] I, uh...
I do realize I said
to make yourself
at home, but perhaps I...
You do not need
to finish the thought!
We will leave
as soon as possible.
[crickets chirping]
[KAZUMA]
I slept so much this afternoon
that I'm wide awake, now.
Midnight snack time.
[sighs]
Totally sucks that
we're leaving tomorrow.
- [thuds]
- [gasps]
Is that Aqua?
[CHRIS]
There aren't any guards.
Maybe I'm being paranoid?
[gasps] Yes!
It's my last night here
and I'm hitting the jackpot!
Thank you so much, Eris,
the Goddess of luck!
[CHRIS]
Hm?
I'm feeling the weirdest
presence all of a sudden.
[KAZUMA]
Lurk.
- [CHRIS] Guess it's nothing.
- Dat, dat, dat, dat, dat, da.
[CHRIS]
So, Detect Treasure says
what I'm looking for
should be over this way.
Pounce! Gotcha!
[Chris screams]
[KAZUMA] Time to come along
quietly, you jerk!
You picked
the wrong mansion to rob!
And you're not
dealing with some
two-bit
security guard, either!
I've taken down
Devil King generals,
so there's no way
you're gonna escape
this place! -[CHRIS] Stop it!
Wait a minute, are you?
[KAZUMA]
Hang on,
where have I heard
that voice before?
[CHRIS]
Hey, is that you, Kazuma?
Listen, you really
need to watch
where you're
putting your hands!
I'm only restraining
a trespasser, that's all.
It's me, okay?
[Chris sobbing]
Chris is the noble thief
they were talking about.
Who'll marry me now?
Well, what did you expect?
I thought
you were stealing stuff!
I don't understand, Kazuma!
What are you even doing here?
What?
So, Darkness is also here?
That's bad! Very bad!
She's gonna be so mad
if she finds out!
There's a pretty good chance
they won't kill you
if you just apologize.
Pay your debt to society.
But you've got it all wrong!
I'm doing this for a perfectly
good reason!
[both gasp]
He didn't hear us.
Well, I suppose
I owe you an explanation.
- So, I'll tell you the truth.
- Hm?
- It started way--
- Stop,
- I don't wanna know!
- And why not?
'Cause this is how I get
dragged into trouble
every single time!
Yeah but, still...
Uh, whatever!
Your secret's safe with me!
Right now, you've gotta
hurry up and leave!
Fine, but I could
use your help.
I was kind of hoping you--
Huh. -Hmm.
I do not wanna hear it!
Besides, think about it!
You know as well as I do
that the lord of this place
is a real pervert, right?
If he sees you've been
captured, then look out.
[gasps]
[DARKNESS]
I think I heard something.
I-I'll head out
for tonight, then!
I can explain everything
some another time.
Don't even bother!
Wait, you oughta tie me up
before you take off!
That way I can just
tell 'em you escaped!
O-Okay! Now Bind!
- [groaning]
- See ya!
[thuds]
[groaning]
Kazuma! Are you all right?
- Were you just hit with Bind?
- Where's the thief?
I hate to say it,
but right at the last second,
they got away.
Man, I was careless!
Could one of you
please untie me?
They have escaped then,
so are you injured?
What did the thief look like?
Uh, it, uh...
It was a guy wearing
a weird-looking mask, I think.
And he might've
been even tougher
than a Devil King general, too.
N-No way. He was that fearsome?
That must've been rough, then.
You sure are wrapped up tight.
Can you even move
at all right now?
What do you think?
It's too bad 'cause I had him
right where I
wanted him, but...
Ah, just hurry and untie me.
This sucks.
Hmm?
- Huh.
- [AQUA] Uh, Kazuma.
This might not be
the best time to say it,
but I owe you a huge apology.
Am I missing something here?
Yeah, well, um...
So, you know how you
never came back again
after Princess Iris took you
away to the castle?
[KAZUMA]
Huh? Yeah.
I started randomly
digging around in your room
because I was really bored.
And then, I...
I found a doll-looking thingie
you must've made
and I accidentally broke it.
You little...
That's fine!
Don't worry. I can fix it.
Now, if you'll untie me.
That's it? You forgive me?
Guess I might as well
clear the air
while I've got the chance.
There, in your bedroom,
I figured it would be okay
since you weren't around,
so I started downing
some booze.
Truth is when I was drinking,
cleaning up snack crumbs
and empty bottles
just seemed like a real pain.
So I just got hammered
and ended up breaking
a lot of other stuff, too.
Sorry about that!
[chuckles]
[KAZUMA]
I could strangle her!
N-No problem!
'Cause we're good friends!
And I am the one who
didn't come back home.
Now, if you could just
untie me, then that would be...
- Huh?
- You know.
Regarding
this particular situation,
Aqua does have a valid point.
I have a sneaking suspicion
that we're in for some fun.
[gasps]
Hey, what's going on here?
- Please help me!
- Go on, then!
Say you regret being
such a cocky bastard lately!
Apologize for the endless grief
you have put me through!
"I am so sorry
for humiliating you!"
- Say it! Now!
- I'm sorry!
I'm sorry
for causing you trouble!
Not a bad try,
but I need to hear you
say that again, Kazuma!
You remember what you said!
Come on,
how many points was it?
Exactly how many points
does my Explosion magic get?
You've gotta stop! The reason
you remember that stuff
- is 'cause it's been said once!
- Oh, no,
go on and say it!
Don't be shy!
Just spit it out!
What are you waiting for?
Come on!
[DARKNESS] I had no idea
that turning the tables
could be so fun!
How do you like it? Huh? Huh?
♪
[RAIN]
I see.
Despite all of your
confident assertions,
you still failed the task.
You said "The thief wore a mask
and was extremely
formidable," right?
Yeah, that's right!
But I wouldn't say the whole
thing was a total failure!
'Cause, if I hadn't been there,
who knows what would've
happened to old man Aldarp?
He was worthless.
Indeed,
quite a worthless adventurer.
[gasps]
[sighs]
Sir Kazuma has
courageously battled
the Devil King's generals.
So, I'm quite certain
this thief must've been
a serious threat.
Hold on, Kazuma--
[gasps]
Huh.
I see.
Well, in any event,
I must thank you.
Rather than failing
to apprehend the devious thief,
you successfully stopped him
from stealing anything.
So, in my eyes you've done
nothing to earn derision.
[gasps]
You should be grateful
for Princess Iris' mercy.
But that said,
there's no reason for you
to remain in the castle.
Forthwith, take your leave.
Huh.
Hm.
♪
The bubbly around the capital
sure doesn't live up
to all the hype.
Souvenir shopping, huh?
How insensitive
can one person be?
I'm pretty depressed here.
It's not like we have
anything else to do, right?
You little!
I can't find
anything round here.
Michael from Axel
has way better stuff
in his store, to be honest.
So, who the hell
is this Michael guy?
You've turned into a real
"social butterfly"
back home, haven't you?
Just the other day,
some guy came by the mansion
and left a bunch
of expensive meat
to thank you
for healing him up.
[gasps] Wait,
nobody said anything to me
and I don't remember getting
any meat! So, where did it go?
Simple, Darkness cooked it
and then we both ate--
Excuse me?
And I didn't get one bite?
You've got a lot of explaining
to do, you know that? -Oh, Aqua
what a coincidence
running into you out here!
[KAZUMA]
Huh?
♪
Who are you?
It seems you still have
a wonderful sense
of humor, Aqua.
Okay, this guy is being
a little too familiar
and it's so weird.
Hi, it's, uh, it's me.
The Sword Master you
granted the cursed sword to
some time ago.
It's Katsuragi!
You remember him, don't ya?
I told you
My name's Mitsurugi!
It's Mitsurugi!
[KAZUMA] Guess it'll take
more than his name.
He's got the cursed sword.
- Remember that?
- Yeah.
Come on, you didn't actually
forget my name, did you?
Why don't you say the whole
thing, just to make sure?
I mean, I could do that,
but it feels like you're
putting me on the spot.
It's Kyouya! If you've
forgotten, then just admit it!
My name is Kyouya Mitsurugi!
[sighs]
Whatever.
- But, more importantly, Aqua.
- [AQUA] Huh.
[MITSURUGI] I'd like to express
my gratitude for our reunion.
- What, for me?
- Hm.
It's just something that
I picked up during my travels.
Though, I'm not confident
you like this sort of thing.
[KAZUMA]
Oh, isn't he such a gentleman?
What a move!
I am so pissed off!
Hm.
This ring's way too small
for my finger.
[Mitsurugi groans]
[MITSURUGI] Could I get three
glasses of bubbly, please?
♪
[snoring]
[CHRIS]
Wake up.
Come on, wake up already.
[groaning]
- Come on, Kazu--
- Intruder!
[Chris screams]
[CHRIS]
Hey, it's only me, okay?
Cut it out!
Whoa, don't touch me there!
Darkness! Darkness! Help!
[KAZUMA]
Oh, it's you, Chris.
Who did you think it was?
Now, tell me the truth!
When you sprang out of bed
and jumped on me,
did you know I was?
First, you roll up in
a guy's room for a booty call,
then scream when you get
touched? Is this a honey trap?
It wasn't a booty call
or a honey trap!
I already told you that
I was gonna come by here
and explain, so that's
exactly what I did!
- Hmm.
- [CHRIS] Hang on!
Don't suddenly pretend
you can't hear me!
I thought I already told you
I didn't wanna hear it!
You should try
coming back later!
Like, oh, I don't know,
next year, maybe?
But I've gotta
handle this, now!
Come on,
just hear me out! Please?
Please, please, please,
please, please, please, please.
Okay, damn it! Go ahead!
For some time,
I've been gathering
these incredibly powerful
and rare items
called Divine Treasures.
Huh, Divine Treasures?
Sounds like trouble,
so can we stop now?
Just listen!
These items are normally
only given to adventurers
with dark hair, dark eyes,
and funny-sounding names.
Really weird ones
just like yours.
Don't call my name weird. Hm?
[KAZUMA] The reincarnated
people get cheat items
when they show up here.
Is that what she's looking for?
Each one of them
has different effects.
Some can do
a whole lot of damage,
while others can bring
incredible wealth.
Wealth?
[gasps]
Huh.
♪
- That was you?
- Listen, I'm sorry, okay?
But they're more dangerous
than you can even imagine!
So, they all need
to be gathered up!
By who and what for?
Well, I, uh...
My client says that
I'm not allowed to share
any of the details.
- I don't care, then!
- [screams]
But this is
the most important part!
I can sense the presence
of an amazing treasure
coming from the castle!
You've gotta be kidding me!
That's the most obvious thing
you could've said!
Yep! And, with that in mind,
I wanted to ask you
for some help.
I knew it! I'm through
getting mixed up in bad news!
[gasps]
You have the Night Vision
skill, don't you?
Along with Lurk
and Enemy Detection?
Couldn't you use those to try
and help me out a little bit?
Stop trying to turn me
into a criminal!
Man, I was right
about all this!
There is no way
I'm gonna help you!
So, you might
as well forget it!
Ah, come on! Don't be
like that, you big meanie!
Get out! You better get
outta here right this minute!
'Cause if you don't,
I'll use Bind
before harassing you sexually!
- Huh.
- [Kazuma groans]
[CHRIS] I'm gonna
head back for now.
We can talk more about
all this stuff tomorrow.
I told you to "quit it!"
Now, bye.
[gasps] All right, I'll let you
off the hook this time!
♪
[sighs]
Damn it.
Man, I wish
I could catch a break.
Ugh, Eris, you have my word.
When I finally
get back to Axel,
then I'll convert
to your church,
so, until I get out there,
please grant me
a little peace and quiet.
Hmm.
[foghorn blaring]
[screams]
[ANNOUNCER 03-A (F)]
Devil King Army alert!
A group belonging
to the Devil King's army
has been deployed
near the capital!
All knights must be ready!
Any high-level adventurers
are now requested to assist!
- [knocking on door]
- Kazuma, hurry up!
Get your gear together.
[KAZUMA]
Can't, sleeping.
This is not the time for jokes!
The Devil King's army is here!
So, every one of us needs
to join the fight!
Sounds like you're the one
joking to me!
You heard what she said
in the announcement, right?
They want
"High-level adventurers"
and I think we all know
I'm pretty "mid!"
Besides, isn't this whole city
supposed to be crawling
with badasses?
I'm sure they can
handle it just fine!
You can be
such a coward sometimes!
Suit yourself! I will take
Aqua and Megumin and go!
Keep trembling in bed,
you low-level adventurer!
Hmph!
[door closes]
[AQUA] No, are you kidding?
That sounds too dangerous!
Why do I have to go?
I only came to the capital
to goof around!
So, there is no way
I'm gonna fight
against the Devil King's army!
You should stop
being so selfish, Aqua!
In these situations, you can
never have too many healers!
Just look at Megumin!
She is absolutely raring to go!
Darkness,
I'm going ahead to confront
- the Devil King's forces.
- [gasps]
If the battle starts
and different factions
become tangled up in a melee,
then I won't even have
a chance to use my magic!
The very first strike
is going to be mine!
And I am betting
my powered-up magic
will both begin and end
the fighting all at once!
[Darkness groans]
Wait, Megumin!
Do not be so reckless!
And, Aqua, just give it up!
Oh, come on, Kazuma!
- I really need your help here!
- [screams]
Why are you guys
always screaming?
There's no reason to butt in
on something this dangerous
and risk our necks.
[gasps]
Hey, hang on a minute.
If I can show off a little
during this thing,
then that might be
what it takes
to get me back in the castle.
I mean, there's already
a bunch of adventurers
with tons of cheats
in the capital!
So I seriously doubt
the bad guys will win.
It's not like I need to head
out there and wipe the floor
with the Devil King's guys
all by myself.
As long as I put on
a decent enough show,
that oughta do the trick!
Enough, Darkness!
I have a terribly bad feeling
about this!
You can have one of my
breakfast sausages, okay?
Let's put this on hold
till tomorrow!
When the royal army finally
arrives out on the battlefield,
they'll see
the smoldering remains
of the Devil King's forces,
and a wizard taking
her well-earned leave.
Yeah, that's what I wanna do!
And now's my big chance!
So, you've got to let me go
before it gets any later!
Kazuma, I need your help!
Do something about these two!
[both gasp]
Listen, Ladies,
the kingdom needs our help.
Off we go!
It's our turn to kick
some major butt!
[whimpering]
[screaming]
[wailing]
[VERDIA]
Strike! Strike!
Howdy!
The weather's great here.
It's me, Verdia!
Y'know, no matter
how many times I...